<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Ryan Rushing, designer</title>
		<description>Ryan is a designer living in the Dallas-area. Sometimes he writes.</description>
		<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
		<atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>The Problem with Infinity</title>
				<description>&lt;h3 id='the_old_days'&gt;The Old Days&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically speaking, making something meant it was tangible, and having more resourses, such as time, money, and natural resources, meant more physical objects could be created. With physical items, there&amp;#8217;s always a one-to-one trade: creating things demands resources, and creating lots of things demands lots of resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After physical objects are made, the one-to-one trade-off carries over into the business world when some form of currency is accepted for the object. You give me this, and I give you that. Simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The written word, whether by printing press or by human hand, has been around for millenia. When Gutenburg invented the printing press in 1450s, he didn&amp;#8217;t change the fundamental limitations of phyics, however, he did increase the effenciecy of making a large number of physical items. More books in less time. After selling the first batch of books, more books need to be made if I want to sell more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, emormous libraries contain an unfathomable number of pages, covers, and letters holding vast amounts of information and stories. And yet, there is a limit to how many physical books can exist. Between the resources it takes to create books and the physical space it takes to store books, we are still faced with limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='infinity_close_enough'&gt;Infinity (Close Enough)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the digital world, space is cheap and abundant. While the available physical space on Earth is decreasing, the space in the digital world seems to be expanding at break-neck speeds. Whether we&amp;#8217;re talking about the &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cloud_computing'&gt;Cloud&lt;/a&gt;, or just personal computers and mobile devices, these all have a vast space incomparable to physical space in their dimensions. The digital world may as well be infinite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our brains find the concept of infinity difficult to understand, and yet we&amp;#8217;re creating products which live solely in that world. We&amp;#8217;re trying to use the same one-to-one model we use with physical items to solve the problems we&amp;#8217;re encountering. A &amp;#8220;you give me this, I give you that&amp;#8221; thought-process doesn&amp;#8217;t quite work when our products aren&amp;#8217;t limited by resources in the same way as physical items. We should approach the problem with a different model altogether with entirely different variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='one_copy_to_rule_them_all'&gt;One Copy to Rule Them All&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to books for a moment. If our magnificent libraries decided to completely replace their entire collection with digital items, they could dramatically reduce the physical space they&amp;#8217;re currently occupying. If they convert all their paper materials into .ePub, .mobi, and PDF files and place them onto servers, you no longer need many amenities physical libraries need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, digital libraries already exist. You don&amp;#8217;t need to drive there, you don&amp;#8217;t need to open a door to walk in, and most importantly, &lt;strong&gt;there is no longer the physical limitation of one copy in existence.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you go to a physical library and check out a book, you now have that book. Although the content may be the same, the book which you&amp;#8217;re holding is unique; to break it down to an unneccsary level, each copy of a book has its own set of molecules unique to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the libriaian will allow you take the book home, you must give a promise to return the book. There&amp;#8217;s our one-to-one model at work. I give you this; you give me that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However when we introduce infinity into the mix, we can check out the book, leave, and the next person in line right behind us can check out the same book. And the next person. And the next person. All the way into infinity, and you&amp;#8217;ll never run out of any of that book. In fact, there are no &amp;#8220;molecules&amp;#8221; at all with digital items, which means they are the exact same item. Clones, if you will. And each time another clone is created and sold, the benefit to the merchant increases exponentially. Our work involved to create the item stays the same, while we continue to generate income. It&amp;#8217;s as close to money growing on trees as we can get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='there_is_a_trade_not_onetoone_though'&gt;There is a Trade, Not One-to-One Though&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a caveat. Since the electronic universe exists &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; this physical universe, we still have to deal with physics. When a book is checked out of a physical library, remember there is more happening than simply a book getting checked out. The door opens when patrons walk in and out causing the heating and cooling system to work a little bit harder; the librarian may have to stop doing one important task in order to check out your book; after you return the book, the shelver has to spend time to put the book back on the shelf in the right location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These little happenings in a physical library are far less in a digital one, but they still exist. Servers have to be cooled, and when 10,000 people download a book in a short amount of time, the servers will work harder and heat up a little more, causing the cooling system to work harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can&amp;#8217;t lend any more books than they have, but in our digital world, we&amp;#8217;re not limited by the number of books. So, what is the magic number of books available to check out?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t think there is a single magic number. The one-to-one trade we&amp;#8217;re using for physical items requires a magic number of one. You give me this, and I give you that. However, our digital universe requires a more complicated thought process; it&amp;#8217;s no longer a one-to-one trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='specifics'&gt;Specifics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href='http://pinboard.in'&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt;, a paid bookmarking service, uses a formula to inform the cost to join: the number of users multiplied by $0.001. So the earlier you join, the cheaper it is. Although the cost to run Pinboard will increase with the number of users, Maciej has implemented a system to handle the scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a million people download an ebook in an hour, the server&amp;#8217;s cost goes up. Maybe the price during high traffic times should go up as well. Maybe if you&amp;#8217;re a patient and frugal shopper, you&amp;#8217;re willing to wait until another time to make the purchase to get a better deal and more value. In the case of the library (where you don&amp;#8217;t have to purchase anything), maybe there are a limited number of ebooks available for download at high peak times, rather than the infinite number of ebooks ready for download at low traffic times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever formula or algorithm we use, we should not use the same simple pricing models for digital items as we&amp;#8217;ve been using with physical items since the invention of trade. Our technologies to create things have changed dramatically, and our economics for digital storefronts should try to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2013/02/20/the-problem-with-infinity</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2013/02/20/the-problem-with-infinity</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>All Magic Tricks Have an Ending</title>
				<description>&lt;img alt='Poof' src='../../../../../img/in-writings/poof.jpg' title='Gone like the wind.' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m fascinated with illusions, especially close-up magic like card tricks. Being a willing participant in a brain-hacking, to witness something impossible, is incredibly exciting and attractive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the magical moments of a trick, logic and reason is pushed out of our minds. We straddle the line between the fantasy world of mind-readers and the uneventful day-to-day reality of life. We know this experience isn&amp;#8217;t actually happening, but for the trick to work, we must suspend disbelief and allow ourselves to be fooled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our reality becomes a bell-shaped curve while we wait for the punchline. Our suspense builds and builds, until the plot twist is revealed, where we see card you signed at the beginning of the trick is now in your wallet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='Showing where the mind explosion happens in a magic trick.' src='../../../../../img/in-writings/bell-curve-mind-explosion.jpg' title='Showing where the mind explosion happens in a magic trick.' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we come off the high point, hours later after the trick is finished, we tell our friends and family about it. We convince them it was impossible, yet it happened, and we use phrases like &amp;#8220;you just had to be there,&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;you wouldn&amp;#8217;t believe me if I told you.&amp;#8221; Our retelling of the story skews logic even more, and the story becomes an illusion in itself, tricking the listener to suspend their belief of your immense gullibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to developing new ideas, we become the magicians. With simple sleight of hand and presentation, we convince our audience this is the pinnacle of reality. This is it; this is what you&amp;#8217;ve been waiting for! The audience allow themselves to be overtaken by this new app, device, or product, and they&amp;#8217;ll spread the word near and far about its amazing abilities and additions to the world. Previously it didn&amp;#8217;t exist, but by a stroke of genius and some coincidence, it now exists in this world. Together we&amp;#8217;ve crossed over and brought something into this world that didn&amp;#8217;t exist before. &lt;em&gt;Couldn&amp;#8217;t exist.&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;#8217;s like bringing in a three-dimensional object into a two-dimensional world, or suddenly being able to see other parts of the electromagnetic spectrum, like radio and ultraviolet waves, rather than only the visible spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all magic tricks to have their desired effect, they must end. Life must return to before the trick happened, because if reality doesn&amp;#8217;t snap back, it&amp;#8217;s no longer a temporary illusion but rather, it&amp;#8217;s a paradigm shift. If &lt;a href='http://youtu.be/VAEw-gtDkO4'&gt;David Copperfield never made the Statue of Liberty reappear&lt;/a&gt;, we would be living in a world without this great American symbol. It would simply be gone. The US would be different, and we&amp;#8217;d probably ban all magicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our products, new ideas, and even artistic talents aren&amp;#8217;t magic tricks. They are no less amazing, or more believable at first exposure, but where magic tricks send us whirling back to reality when they end, our groundbreaking inventions don&amp;#8217;t. They continue on and affect our reality in more ways than a ten minute adrenaline rush, and that&amp;#8217;s more amazing than making the Statue of Liberty vanish into thin air and bringing it back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2013/02/03/all-magic-tricks-have-an-ending</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2013/02/03/all-magic-tricks-have-an-ending</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Importance of Handwriting</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I recently celebrated National Handwriting Day with some people at &lt;a href='http://weld.co/'&gt;Weld&lt;/a&gt;, a coworking space here in Dallas, and although I must admit I&amp;#8217;ve never heard of National Handwriting Day until &lt;a href='http://steedtastic.com/post/40712348305/national-handwriting-day'&gt;Kyle Steed posted about it&lt;/a&gt;, it was a fun time. (Really, since most of us were practiced at drawing letterforms, it became National Lettering Day for us.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='National Handwriting Day handwriting' src='../../../../../img/in-writings/national-handwriting-day.jpg' style='float: left; width: 30%; margin: 20px 20px 20px 0;' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I sat writing the copy of &lt;a href='https://twitter.com/drawingtype/status/294271687027982336'&gt;a Craigslist ad&lt;/a&gt;, the weight of learning and mastering this skill, for both kids and adults, hit me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handwriting develops hand-eye coordination, attention to detail, and patience. We should be able to, on command, produce &lt;em&gt;legible&lt;/em&gt; hand-writings at the minimum, and writings that are enjoyable to read at best. I&amp;#8217;m not necessarily talking about lettering or calligraphy, although some handwriting could double as such, but rather common writing like when taking notes or writing a thank you note. That still a thing, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn to command your own hand into well-written communication, and I have full confidence you&amp;#8217;ll become a more attentive, detail-oriented, patient designer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2013/01/27/the-importance-of-handwriting</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2013/01/27/the-importance-of-handwriting</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What I Have Been Doing</title>
				<description>&lt;h4 id='im_excited_about_my_personal_projects_and_i_thought_id_share_the_few_holding_my_attention_at_the_moment'&gt;I&amp;#8217;m excited about my personal projects, and I thought I&amp;#8217;d share the few holding my attention at the moment.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id='rachel_rushing_rachelrushingcom'&gt;Rachel Rushing (&lt;a href='http://rachelrushing.com'&gt;rachelrushing.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My wife&amp;#8217;s out-dated site needs a drastic update, and I&amp;#8217;m pretty sure it&amp;#8217;s broken in a lot of places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I built it a couple years ago, it was my first responsive, fully Wordpress site, and many mistakes were made. Also, when I designed the logo and identity for Rachel, which is based primarily on story-telling and connecting, I sincerely thought she needed it, but the truth is she doesn&amp;#8217;t &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a logo. A professional, academic emotion, based around her work, should be the core of her identity, not a logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachel&amp;#8217;s artwork is much different than any other graphic design work, and her new site will focus on explaining her thought process, thereby giving it context. Right now she&amp;#8217;s creating anthotypes, using an antique process from the pigment of flowers and other plants. Once everything is said and done, you&amp;#8217;re left with a gorgeous, aromatic, textural work of art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, you&amp;#8217;d see her work in person in a gallery setting, but at the very least, her work deserves a different treatment on her website than a static, flat, scanned graphic. &lt;em&gt;Launch goal: early February&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='misslou_veterans_village_misslouveteransvillagecom'&gt;Miss-Lou Veteran&amp;#8217;s Village (&lt;a href='http://miss-louveteransvillage.com'&gt;miss-louveteransvillage.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a non-profit organization my dad is founding, and I volunteered to help out. He&amp;#8217;s the business side of it, I&amp;#8217;m the design side of it, and we&amp;#8217;re both the idea guys. So far, it&amp;#8217;s just us two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, it&amp;#8217;ll simply be a job search site geared toward unemployed veterans, and eventually, far down the road, a brick-and-mortar trade school/rehabilitation center/housing for homeless vets will be built.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea was sparked by my dad&amp;#8217;s current job. He works for the State of Mississippi to find jobs for veterans, and as you may know, most government sites are pretty terrible to use. In some cases, he has to send people to several terrible websites, and in the end, these men and women are more confused than when they started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many plans in the works, but for now, we&amp;#8217;re focusing on the job-listing website part. &lt;em&gt;Launch goal: early March&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='can_you_define_love_canyoudefinelovecom'&gt;Can you define love? (&lt;a href='http://canyoudefinelove.com'&gt;canyoudefinelove.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my favorite and longest running personal project, which I&amp;#8217;ve worked on my entire professional career. The current site and identity were developed around this time last year and launched on Valentine&amp;#8217;s Day, and since then, I&amp;#8217;ve uploaded about 360 definitions with about 800 to go. Slowly, but surely, they are all going up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By watching the analytics, I&amp;#8217;ve learned a lot about how people use the site, and I see places to improve. Although I&amp;#8217;m not working on a complete redesign like last year, there are a few different angles I&amp;#8217;d like to approach, especially for searching and browsing the hundreds of love definitions. &lt;em&gt;Launch goal: early April&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='the_happy_factory_wecreatehappycom'&gt;The Happy Factory (&lt;a href='http://wecreatehappy.com'&gt;wecreatehappy.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rachel and I absolutely needed to launch this site this summer, after working on it for a couple years. We did, and now we have to make more products. Also, we need to put some effort into marketing and advertising, which could easily be a full-time job in itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By May, I&amp;#8217;d like to have more products for sale and some UX improvements live. &lt;em&gt;Launch goal: beginning of May&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='my_personal_work'&gt;My Personal Work&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m writing, reading, making improvements to this site, drawing lettering, and constantly keeping track of all ideas, not matter how big or small; there are lots of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2013/01/20/what-i-have-been-doing</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2013/01/20/what-i-have-been-doing</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>May I Borrow Your Phone?</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I have a beard and long, uncut hair. I wear old hoodies and boots and beanies, and by the end of the day, I&amp;#8217;m tired and don&amp;#8217;t say much to people on the train.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day I was on my way to meet my wife at a different train station than usual, where she was going to pick me up so we could head over to her studio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled out my phone to call her, but unfortunately, the battery had been drained and my phone was laying lifeless in my palm. I was about 20 minutes from the station, and I needed to get in touch with Rachel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t be afraid to ask anyone a question, however the question I needed to ask this time hinged on whether or not a person trusted me with their phone. Living in a smartphone dominated world means I wasn&amp;#8217;t simply asking to borrow a phone, but rather, I was asking to be trusted with a device which had access to their Email, Calendar, Facebook, Twitter, financal institutions such as Mint or Paypal, Internet history, and of course, Letterpress games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I scoped out the target, a middle-aged woman, who was sitting across the aisle. I took off my thick, dark-green jacket and beanie; my attempt to seem less threating. I start practicing my question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;#8220;Ma&amp;#8217;am, can I please borrow your cell phone?&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;Too forward.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&amp;#8220;Excuse me. May I please borrow your phone?&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;Overly nice, she&amp;#8217;d be suspicious.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&amp;#8220;Hi, excuse me, would you mind if I borrowed your phone for a quick call?&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;Perfect. Friendly, to the point. Just the right amount of information.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train doors shut, and the next station wouldn&amp;#8217;t be for 10 minutes. On this train line, that&amp;#8217;s the longest between stops. She&amp;#8217;ll know this, and realize I have nowhere to run. Plus, the conductor is standing right there! Now is my chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leaning in my seat toward her, &amp;#8220;Hi, excuse me.&amp;#8221; I said to the woman who was very interested in her book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No response. Crap, I didn&amp;#8217;t expect this. That book must be awesome.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit louder, &amp;#8220;Hi, ma&amp;#8217;am?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nothing. Surely she can hear me, right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conductor and I make eye contact and we both shrug.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practically yelling, &amp;#8220;Excuse me, ma&amp;#8217;am?&amp;#8221; &lt;em&gt;She looks up, thank God.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Hi, not sure if you could hear me not.&amp;#8221; I fake laugh. She is not amused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember the script, Ryan!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Would you mind if I borrowed your phone for a quick call? My phone is dead and I need to call my wife who&amp;#8217;s waiting at the final stop.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crap, way too much information. There&amp;#8217;s no way she&amp;#8217;ll believe that.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8221;&amp;#8230;,&amp;#8221; says the bookworm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8221;I&amp;#8217;d&amp;#8230; rather not.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nodding, I barely get out, &amp;#8220;Okay.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What?! Two minutes before this train wreck of a conversation, I saw her sliding her fingertips around the device with the training of an Angry Birds veteran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I realized how much of a gamble this request was. I have no idea if I looked different (perhaps in an alternate universe where sans-beard, I worked in a suit and tie and had the charm of a prince), Jane McNotrust and I would be best friends. In that world we&amp;#8217;d talk about the days when phone batteries lasted nothing short of a week and how phones only placed calls or maybe sent a text message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we don&amp;#8217;t live there. We live in a world of consolidation and efficiency. Because of our investment into this idea of singular devices and connectibility, the request to call a loved one for less than 60 seconds, turns into a stress-inducing judgement call with much more to lose than just a cheap phone and some contact information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Jane left me high and dry, the conductor, having witnessed all this, chuckled and walked over. He reached into his pocket and pulled out his phone and handed it to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quietly laughed, thanked him, and called my wife on his old Motorola Razr. The call quality was exceptional.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/12/01/may-I-borrow-your-phone</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/12/01/may-I-borrow-your-phone</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>User Testing</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday was my first experience testing a site that I designed. (For these tests, we used &lt;a href='http://usertesting.com'&gt;http://usertesting.com&lt;/a&gt;). The users followed a script with tasks, and as they tried to run through the script, they recorded their screens and articulated what they were thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watching the users interact with the site was humbling and quite odd for me. It was a very cool experience to see someone use a site, following the path you intend for them to take to find specific information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/11/07/user-testing</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/11/07/user-testing</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Working Pattern</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Working everyday is hard, and keeping a pattern is difficult. Plans naturally change, yet we willingly tie ourselves to a pattern on which our entire life leans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t drive to work. Thankfully, I&amp;#8217;m able to rely on public transit to get to and from work with no problem. My commute consists of a 20 minute train ride (between two trains), a 20 minute bus ride, and a 20 minute walk. The trains and buses arrive at the same time every day (most of the time), and my walking time is very peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the mornings I leave my apartment at the same time everyday, walk in the &lt;a href='http://kalkomey.com'&gt;Kalkomey&lt;/a&gt; doors at about the same time, sit down at my desk and do work. In the evenings, I leave at the same time everyday and get home at 5:02pm consistently. My wife and I go to bed around 9 pm every night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, my wife and I rely so heavily on our daily repetition, last year we got rid of both our extremely unreliable cars and bought a single, reliable vehicle. Also, since she&amp;#8217;s also a public transit fiend, our car doesn&amp;#8217;t move for most of the week. It&amp;#8217;s glorious. The system that I&amp;#8217;ve subscribed to may seem like a huge headache, and to be honest, when one delay sets off other delays, it is, but this happens rarely. However, the limitations set by my commute are quickly handled by planning ahead, allowing room for error, and not getting angry when things go awry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I used our car more often and owned a smartphone hooked into the internet, keeping schedule would be &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; difficult for me, not less difficult. Traps like looking at Reddit for a few more minutes, not showering until a few minutes later, or getting an extra 30 minutes of sleep has caused tardiness more often than I&amp;#8217;d like to admit. I thought I could spare the time, since I controlled my pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the environment I&amp;#8217;ve set up, I don&amp;#8217;t make decisions about the perfect timing to beat traffic, nor do I think about the last second I can wait to wake up in the morning. Those plans are out of my hand, which allows me to focus on accomplishing more important things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/11/05/working-pattern</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/11/05/working-pattern</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Learning Agile</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been on the UX team at &lt;a href='http://kalkomey.com/'&gt;Kalkomey&lt;/a&gt; for about three weeks now, and I&amp;#8217;ve learned lots. One thing I&amp;#8217;ve learned about is Agile and &lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scrum_(development'&gt;Scrum&lt;/a&gt;, and although the specific lingo is still very new to me, I&amp;#8217;m getting the hang of it and cannot imagine another way to develop web apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary idea of Agile is this: focus on a set of features for a time, then release it. Yes those features (or “user stories” as they are sometimes called) could be improved, yes there could be more of them, but the point is to get it out there. Once it&amp;#8217;s released and in a live “beta test” of sorts, watch how users interact with it, take notes, and start the process again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iteration is the key. Iterate on the features that users use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this may seem like common sense, it isn&amp;#8217;t. In fact, it&amp;#8217;s against my nature as a designer to release something not packed with features, which have the tiniest bit of attention built into them. However, in web/software development, the “&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Release_early,_release_often'&gt;release early, release often&lt;/a&gt;” model makes the most sense. Don&amp;#8217;t misunderstand me, the Agile method isn&amp;#8217;t meant release incomplete features, but rather, the goal is release a small number of completed features, which are core to your app/product first. Once need arises for more stuff, introduce more stuff, but only when you need it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love this idea so much that I&amp;#8217;ve incorporated it into my personal life - even housework. Focusing my attention on doing one thing at a time, with a larger goal in mind, has taken a lot of the stress away from cleaning the entire apartment. Breaking my chores into bite-size pieces helps not get overwhelmed when I see the &lt;em&gt;whole&lt;/em&gt; apartment needs a top to bottom cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize many of you have been practicing this method for a while, but if you&amp;#8217;ve never tried it out, give it a shot. You won&amp;#8217;t develop apps the same way again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/10/26/learning-agile</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/10/26/learning-agile</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Don't Assume</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I once saw a homeless guy give a burrito to another homeless guy, and a few minutes later give another burrito to someone else. My misconception that all homeless people were out for themselves was blown out of the water. The idea that they were less fortunate because they had less money, left my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In design, it&amp;#8217;s important for us not to assume anything. We can&amp;#8217;t guess what others will do, because people surprise us. They will do something unexpected, and if our decisions were based on personal preference or bad research, we&amp;#8217;ll be caught off guard. I try not to assume when it comes to design. It&amp;#8217;s not really about being awesome, it&amp;#8217;s about paying attention.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/10/03/dont-assume</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/10/03/dont-assume</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On Drinking Sprite</title>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;By definition, a sprite is an elf or fairy, so next time you drink Sprite&lt;sup&gt;&amp;reg;&lt;/sup&gt;, imagine you&amp;#8217;re consuming the life-force of a magical elfin fairy creature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your pain is my gain, Tinkerbell.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
				<link>http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/08/27/sprite</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/writing/2012/08/27/sprite</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
